Going through the last subject, because
we talked about UX, customer discovery,
experiments, and now we talk about user
persona. That's your target customer.
And it is a fictional representation of
a type of customer. It's a fictional
representation. It's not Gigel.
From Vaslui that I know, it's the friend
of someone. No, it's Gigel, a fictional
representation, like an actor, okay?
That represents everyone that has
specific characteristics.
And they answer the question, "Who are
we building this product for?"
So, and it's at the heart of the design
design process. Usually, we
invest a lot into
finding the right persona for a specific
product or
usually we find first the persona, its
problem, and then drill down to who will
buy.
What are the relevant questions? What
age group do they represent? What's the
group of people that actually does those
actions that we are targeting with our
solutions and they have no restrictions
between each other?
Because when we look, for example, in a
product, we might have different user
personas. So,
let's say we are building a tool for
children.
Um
children are
um
don't have money, so they won't pay for
that product. They also don't have
They have their maybe their own device,
but they're not managing it.
Therefore, we also have the parents.
So, we'll have at least two personas. If
we're targeting kids
under
10 years old versus kids over 10 years
old, again, two different personas.
If we're targeting
um an app for kids that also makes sense
um, educationally. So, we also have
teachers.
Let's say. Another persona comes in.
Each of this persona completes a set of
action in the platform.
And they have restrictions between each
other, right? So, someone controls the
actions of the other. So, you need to
build all of these personas and discuss
with all of them.
What is their current approach? How do
they solve this problem that you tell me
that they're having? How are they trying
to solve it if they are solving it? And
how much does it cost them really? Why
do they have this existing work model?
Why don't they have something simpler?
Why didn't they go in a direction to
solve that problem? Maybe they don't
know. Maybe they didn't try. Why didn't
they try? They don't have money. They
don't have tools. They don't want to
install that. You need to explore all of
that when you go into customer
discovery. Because otherwise, you'll
just assume that you are solving a
problem, but maybe they don't want to
solve it or they don't know how to solve
it or they tried and it didn't work. You
need to know if they did that.
What are their common needs, their
pains, their goals?
What do they actually want? Not from
your product, but in general. What are
their needs? And what are what is their
purpose? Why do you want why do they
want something? Because when you want,
for example, an application for your
uh, your child,
uh, you want that
You don't want specifically an app that
would cover something for for them. You
are investing in a bigger purpose,
right? So, you need to understand that.
You need to understand the whole
uh, problem space and where you fit in
their
overall purpose.
These are some examples of two different
personas for a shopping app. Uh it's
Maria and Florin, very different
personas, specifically on technology
needs, uh financial, motivation, and so
on.
So, when Florin buys uh from
um and orders from a delivery of food
delivery app, uh they um are looking at
uh price ranges. They it's they split
their delivery cost with their friends.
Um maybe uh he'll he's looking for um
yeah, optimizing costs in general and
have this nutritional information
because he's into nutrition and sports
and stuff. Um looking at promotions is
something that is very useful for him.
Um whereas for Maria,
um
maybe she doesn't have uh this
experience with technology so much. She
especially uses uh only her phone,
maybe.
Um
she cannot compare with other shops,
with other products. Uh she doesn't want
to have her product selected by other
people.
Um
so, they don't have a stock for local
products or she would want that or to
filter for that.
So, here you can see two different
personas. If you are trying to sell a
product to both of them, you need to
cater to their needs.
Because if you only cater for one, they
will only use it. Uh only they will use
it, and Maria will not be your customer.
And the other way uh around, okay?